Sandeep Chauhan

+91-6005030657

<u>Stackoverflow Github LinkedIn</u> <u>sandeepsajan0@gmail.com</u> <u>Moradabad, India</u>

Summary I'm a Software Developer with 2-3 years of volunteer experience in application development. I have major experience with Python and Django. I love to work remotely with global developers. I always welcome the new technology-based projects. I have good problem-solving skills. I am a quick learner and passionate about scaling the applications.

Experience

Part-time Contract at Remote Inning(Full-stack developer)

Jan 2020 - April 2020

- Developed the backend APIs with the JWT Authentication for a single-tenant and multi-tenant architecture applications.
- Integrate Wagtail CMS with a static site template, create its models, templates, templatetags and etc.
- Upgrade the cookiecutter-django-foundation with the foundation site's version.

Intern at Spoonshot (Full-stack developer)

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Scaling and performance improvements of web crawlers implemented using Python/Django.
- Deployed a proxymanager for scraping framework on Django server with Redis.
- Dockerize the scraping framework and scale it with mongodb, celery workers and aws.
- Implement monitoring systems with Grafana and influxdb.

Google Summer of Code Student

Apr 2018 - Aug 2018

- Python based implementation of <u>Hydra Client</u>.
- Implemented Hydra Client with the datastore Redis which also works as a cache for Hydrus.
- Developed a web app using flask for hydra-client demo.

Open Source Contribution

Hydra Ecosystem

- hydra-python-agent One of the main contributors who have built this project.
 Implemented Redis as a graph database using redisgraph and Cypher. Also created a Docker env., write tests, use designing patterns and etc.
- **hydrus** Add UUID in database and also add auto documentation using sphinx and fix some easy issues.

- hydra-astrodemo Created a demo for hydra-client using flask which also using the hydra-parser and hydrus server.
- http-apis.github.io Write documention for all the work done by me and also for some other projects related to my work.

Projects

Wagtail-centrarium

Portfolio site, using a static template(centrarium), with the great Wagtail CMS features. Portfolio sites can be generated in less than 2 mins with the help of this project.

Go Web App

A Web app implemented with Golang using Redis as a database having features routing, authentication, middleware, comments, error handling. It is a good reference for beginners because of its modules and good structure.

Reactjs Projects

- o Calculator
- o router-sample
- friends passion(Beginner-friendly project to iterate over json data)
- ReactSwapi Api(React app to consume api and show data of swapi.co)

Friends

An anonymous web chat app implemented with Python, Django, Reactjs with database sqlite3 have some great functionalities like authentication, public and private groups(without showing users), API's, messaging/posting, API's data presenting using Reactjs.

Social Networking

A blogpost web app which is implemented using Python, Django and PostgreSQL as a database having features like authentication, manage profiling, blogs posting (with date and name). It is live or deployed on heroku.

Education

Bachelor of Technology(2016-2020(expected))
 Shri Mata Vaishno Devi University, katra, India

Miscellaneous

Student mentor/guide at The CodeClub, SMVDU.

Skills

Backend Development: Python(Django, Wagtail), Golang **Frontend Development:** React.js, HTML and CSS, JS **Databases**: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Mongodb, sqlite

Operating System: Linux(ubuntu)

Other tools: Git, Bash, Docker, Celery, RabbitMQ, Grafana, influxdb, AWS